New decade. New rules.
Scream 4 is a horror, mystery film directed by Wes Craven.
Ten years after the original Woodsboro murders, one of the survivors returns home to promote their new book
about surviving trauma, only for a new Ghostface killer to emerge, targeting a new group of teens.
Dewey Riley, played by David Arquette.
Sidney Prescott, played by Neve Campbell.
Gale Weathers-Riley, played by Courteney Cox.
Jill Roberts, played by Emma Roberts.
Kirby Reed, played by Hayden Panettiere.
Deputy Perkins, played by Anthony Anderson.
Scream 4 (stylized as SCRE4M) is a 2011 American slasher film
directed by Wes Craven and written by Kevin Williamson.
Produced by Outerbanks Entertainment and distributed by Dimension Films, it is the sequel
to Scream 3 (2000) and the fourth installment in the Scream film series.
The film stars David Arquette, Neve Campbell, Courteney Cox, Emma Roberts, Hayden Panettiere, Anthony Anderson, Alison Brie,
Adam Brody, Rory Culkin, Marielle Jaffe, Erik Knudsen, Mary McDonnell, Marley Shelton and Nico Tortorella.
The film takes place on the fifteenth anniversary of the original Woodsboro murders from Scream (1996) and involves Sidney Prescott
(Campbell) returning to the town after ten years, where Ghostface once again begins killing students from Woodsboro High.
Like its predecessors, Scream 4 combines the violence of the slasher genre with elements of
black comedy and "whodunit" mystery to satirize the clichés of film remakes.
The film also provides commentary on the extensive usage of
social media and the obsession with internet fame.
The series was originally intended to be a trilogy.
However, in June 2008, the Weinstein Company announced a fourth film was in
development, with Craven confirmed to direct in March 2010.
In September 2009, Arquette, Campbell, and Cox were announced to be returning, after
which the casting process lasted between April and September 2010.
Principal photography began in June 2010 and ended in September that
same year, taking place in and around Ann Arbor, Michigan.
Scenes set around Woodsboro High School were filmed at
Woodworth Middle School in Dearborn, Michigan.
Ehren Kruger, who previously wrote the screenplay for Scream 3,
was hired for script rewrites during production.
Reshoots were filmed in early 2011, following test screenings.
Scream 4 premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on April 11, 2011, and was
released in the United States on April 15, 2011, by Dimension Films.
The film received mixed reviews from critics at the time of release, earning praise for the performances,
direction, and humor but criticism for the lack of scares and reliance on clichéd formulas.
However, many considered it to be an improvement over its predecessor, and it has enjoyed several positive
reappraisals since, particularly for its prescient examination of the negative impact of social media.
It grossed $97 million worldwide on a budget of $40 million,
becoming the lowest-grossing film in the Scream franchise.
Scream 4 was the final film to be directed by Craven before his death in 2015.
It was followed by the anthology television series Scream (2015–2019), which was developed for MTV
without the involvement of the main cast or crew of the films, although Roger L.
Jackson, who provided the voice of Ghostface in the films,
returned to voice Ghostface in the third season.
A fifth film, Scream, was released on January 14, 2022, by Paramount Pictures.
The film explores themes of rescue, mask, sheriff, jealousy, dark comedy.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.